finereaderonline.com 2018-05-14

# Privacy Notice - ABBYY FineReader Online

ABBYY USA Software House, Inc. (" **ABBYY** ") has created this website (the " **Website** " or the " **Site** ") to provide a platform for sales, registration, and support for ABBYY's character recognition, data capture, linguistics, and translation products and services.

ABBYY is committed to maintaining your privacy. This Privacy Notice (" **Privacy Notice** ") outlines our privacy practices, including the types of information that you may provide through our Website while purchasing or registering Products, accessing support services, or while participating in other services we offer through the Website (collectively, the " **Products and Services** "), how we use such information and the notice and choice affected individuals have regarding our use of and their ability to correct that information. Our Privacy Notice applies to any visitor to the Website (collectively, " **you** "), including (i) casual visitors to our Site, who do not participate in the Services (" **Site Visitors** "), and (ii) individuals who visit the Website to purchase or register Products or participate in our Services (" **Registered Users** "). In addition, this Privacy Notice also applies to users of our Products, as specified in the relevant End User License Agreement ("EULA"). The terms " **ABBYY** ," " **we** " and " **us** " refer to ABBYY USA Software House, Inc.

**1\. NOTICE.**

**1.1. The Types of Information You May Provide.** Information you may provide or that we may collect from you while visiting our Site or while participating in our Services falls into three broad categories: (i) personally identifiable information, (ii) activities information, and (iii) aggregate information.

**1.2. Personally Identifiable Information.** We use the term " **Personally Identifiable Information** " to mean any information that could reasonably be used to identify you, including your name, address, e-mail address, birth date, financial information, photograph, telephone number, or any combination of information that could be used to identify you.

**1.3. Activities Information.** We use the term " **Activities Information** " to refer to information collected by so-called "persistent identifiers" such as cookies and web beacons. Unlike Personally Identifiable Information, Activities Information does not directly identify a particular person; the information, however, is or can potentially be linked to a particular computer or device. Activities Information is collected and used in the manner described below.

**1.4. Anonymous Information.** " **Anonymous Information** " is information that does not identify you, and may include statistical information concerning, for example, your use of our Products and Services, your access to content on our Website, or the pages on our Site that you visit most frequently.

**2\. CONSENT.**

It is your decision whether to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information, and we will only use this type of information for certain purposes if you opt-in as provided in Section 3 (Choice). We have structured our Website so that you may visit our Site and review selected information about our Products and Services without revealing your identity or providing any Personally Identifiable Information. Please read this Privacy Notice carefully. Once you consent to the Privacy Notice's terms, it creates legal obligations on you and on ABBYY. By accessing and using our Website, you are acknowledging that you have read and understood this Privacy Notice and agree to be legally bound by it. Providing your Personally Identifiable Information in connection with using this Website confirms your agreement to be bound by this Privacy Notice. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Notice, please refrain from using our Site.

**3\. CHOICE.**

**3.1. Registered Users can Opt-In.** Registered Users will be provided the opportunity to "opt-in" to receiving bulletins, updates, the ABBYY newsletter, or other unsolicited communications that are marketing-related materials. Registered Users will also be afforded an opportunity to opt-in to ABBYY's use or disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information for a purpose other than those disclosed in this Notice. If you do not opt-in and affirmatively choose to allow use of your Personally Identifiable Information for these purposes, we will not do so. Registered Users expressly agree to these uses by opting in.

**3.2. Exceptions to Opt-In Choice.** Please understand that Registered Users will not be given a choice regarding receiving formal notices concerning operation of this Website, the Products and Services you have purchased, downloaded or registered for, and legal and other related notices concerning your relationship with ABBYY and this Site.

**4\. COLLECTION.**

**4.1. Our Collection of Personally Identifiable Information.** We and certain service providers operating on our behalf collect Personally Identifiable Information from you in connection with your use of the Site. Personally Identifiable Information is collected only for the purposes identified in this Notice. The following further summarizes the Personally Identifiable Information that is collected:

**4.1.1. Registration Information.** If you choose to register with us in order to receive technical support, information and discounts on newer versions and updates for our products, and other benefits we may provide, (regardless of whether your purchase was made through ABBYY or one of our resellers or distributors), you may register with us in one of five (5) ways: (i) within the ABBYY product itself; or (ii) by completing the registration form on our website; or (iii) by email; or (iv) by telephone; or (v) by fax. Whichever registration method you select, it will specify the information which you must provide in order to receive these benefits, which may include such items as (i) name and title; (ii) company name, size and industry; (iii) email address, (iv) telephone number, and (iv) purchase information. The registration may additionally request information, which you may, at your option, choose to provide or withhold. If you fail to register your product with us in one of the foregoing specified manners, we will be unable to provide you with technical support. And, if you fail to register your product with us, but thereafter seek technical support from us, at that point, we will collect your name, email address and country in order to provide you with the support services. All information you provide in connection with the registration process is collected by one of our Affiliates and is shared with us.

**4.1.2. Purchase of Products and Services.** We collect Personally Identifiable Information, including contact information (such as name, email address, and shipping address) and financial information (such as payment card number, expiration date and security code), in connection with your ordering and purchasing of Products and Services through our Website using a credit or debit card.

4.1.3. Email Addresses. Both Site Visitors and Registered Users may wish to provide us with comments and feedback concerning our Site and Products generally. By communicating with us for these purposes, you may provide us with your email address and other Personally Identifiable Information.

**4.1.4. Questionnaires and Surveys.** Our Website may allow Site Visitors and Registered Users to participate in surveys and questionnaires, which we may post on the Site from time to time. You are free to choose whether you participate in a survey or questionnaire. We may ask that, in addition to providing your responses, you also provide Personally Identifiable Information. We advise you to use discretion in including any Personally Identifiable Information that would enable a third party reviewing your response to link the response to you.

**4.1.5. Use of Data Brokers.** We may acquire from data brokers marketing lists that contain Personally Identifiable Information, and may use such information collected for marketing purposes.

**4.2. Our Collection of Activities Information.** We and certain service providers operating on our behalf collect Activities Information about your activity on our Site. The following further summarizes the Activities Information that is collected:

**4.2.1. IP Addresses; Logs.** ABBYY may automatically receive and record information in our server logs from your browser, including your IP address (the Internet address of your computer), your computer's name, the type and version of your web browser, referrer addresses, and other generally-accepted log information. We may also record page views (hit counts) and other general statistical and tracking information.

**4.2.2. Cookies.** A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, which is sent to your browser from a website's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. We may use cookies on our website.

**4.2.3. Click-Throughs.** We may send email messages, which use a "click-through URL" linked to content on our Website. When you click one of these URLs, you pass through our web server before arriving at the destination web page. If you prefer not to be tracked simply do not click text or graphic links in the email.

**4.3. Our Collection of Anonymous Information.** We may collect Anonymous Information through features of the software supporting the Website and use this information as follows:

**4.3.1. Site Visitors Only Provide Anonymous Information.** As indicated above, you may use our Site without registering or submitting any information to us. In that case, the only information we collect from your visit will be Anonymous Information that does not identify you in any way.

**4.3.2. Questionnaires and Surveys.** Our Website may allow Site Visitors and Registered Users to participate in surveys and questionnaires, which we may post on the Site from time to time. You are free to choose whether you participate in a survey or questionnaire.

**4.3.3. Computer Configuration.** We may collect information about your operating system and browser, as well as the presence of any software that our Website may require to operate with your computer, or other third party software on your computer. This information is kept strictly confidential and is not shared with third parties, except as provided for in this Privacy Notice.

**5\. USE.**

**5.1. Our Use of Personally Identifiable Information.** ABBYY will only use Personally Identifiable Information as set out in this Notice. We will not use Personally Identifiable Information for purposes other than which it was provided unless you "opt-in" in accordance with Section 3 (Choice). As provided in Section 8 (Disclosure to Third Parties) we will only share Personally Identifiable Information that you choose to provide to us via the Website with third parties as expressly disclosed in this Notice. We will not share it in any other way.

**5.1.1. Registration Information.** Registration information is used by ABBYY for internal purposes in providing the Products and Services. As provided in Section 5.1.4 (Informational Notices and Bulletins; Marketing), we may also use this information to send marketing materials and informational notices.

**5.1.2. Purchasing Products.** Information collected in connection with purchasing Products is used for billing purposes, filling orders, and contacting you in the event that there is an issue with your order. Please note that ABBYY does not directly collect or store your financial account information – instead, we use a reputable company (the " **Payment Processing Company** ") to collect and process your payment information. Rest assured, however, that we have taken steps to ensure that the Payment Processing Company protects Personally Identifiable Information it collects from you in compliance with our Privacy Notice.

**5.1.3. Email Addresses.** We use email addresses for the purpose for which you submit this information. We may also use this information to send marketing materials and informational notices, if you have "opted-in" in accordance with Section 3 (Choice).

**5.1.4. Informational Notices and Bulletins; Marketing.** Periodically, we may choose to send news, bulletins, marketing materials, or other information to Registered Users in the interest of improving our Products and Services and developing and offering new Products and Services, or permitting others to develop and offer such products and services. We will use Personally Identifiable Information to send such communications and share Personally Identifiable Information with outside service providers, Affiliates, or other entities in connection with such purposes. We will undertake such communications provided that you first opt-in to receive these communications as provided in Section 3 (Choice), and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that third party recipients of your Personally Identifiable Information honor your decision not to opt-in, provided that ABBYY will have no liability for such third parties’ failure to do so.

**5.1.5. Questionnaires and Surveys.** Regarding questionnaires and surveys, we use any information you provide to us for the purposes for which you submit the information. We may also use this information to send marketing materials and informational notices. Survey and questionnaire information may be used by ABBYY for the purposes of monitoring or improving the use and appeal of this Site and our Products and Services.

**5.2. Our Use of Activities Information.** We and certain service providers operating on our behalf use Activities Information about your activity on our Site. In addition, advertisers and other third parties might use Activities Information via our Site. The following further summarizes how the Activities Information is used.

**5.2.1. IP Addresses; Logs.** General statistics and tracking information will be aggregated with that of other users in order to understand how our Website is being used, and for security and monitoring purposes.

**5.2.2. Cookies.** We may use cookies to provide you with a tailored user experience and to make it easier for you to use a website upon a future visit. We use cookies to recognize you when you return to our Website. You may set your browser so that it does not accept cookies. Cookies must be enabled on your web browser, however, if you wish to access certain personalized features of our Products and Services.

**5.2.3. Tags.** We may use so-called "pixel tags" — small graphic images (also know as "web beacons" or "single-pixel GIFS") — to tell us what parts of our website have been visited or to measure the effectiveness of searches customers perform on our Site. Pixel tags also enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they inform us whether emails have been opened, to help ensure that our messages are of interest to our Registered Users. **None of this data includes Personally Identifiable Information and these types of emails will only be sent to you if you "Opt-in" in accordance with Section 3 (Choice).** If any Personally Identifiable Information is collected using such tools, it will be subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice.

**5.2.4. Click-Throughs.** We track click-through data to help determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked simply do not click text or graphic links in the email.

**5.2.5. Computer Configuration.** We use the information collected about your computer configuration to determine if your computer is compatible with our system.

**5.3. Our Use of Anonymous Information.** We use Anonymous Information to analyze the effectiveness of our Site, to improve our Products and Services, and for other similar purposes. In addition, from time to time, we may undertake or commission statistical and other summary analyses of the general behavior and characteristics of users of our Products and Services and the characteristics of visitors at our Site, and may share Anonymous Information with third parties, including third party ad service providers or advertisers (" **Advertisers** "). Anonymous Information provided to third parties will not allow anyone to identify you, or determine anything personal about you.

**6\. RETENTION AND DISPOSAL.**

We do not retain Personally Identifiable Information longer than needed in order to process your transaction and maintain our customer records. ABBYY has a retention structure in place and complies with applicable laws and regulations surrounding the disposal and retention of documents and files containing Personally Identifiable Information. Please note that, similar to the situation where we delete your Personally Identifiable Information on your request, it may not be technically or commercially feasible to remove this information completely, due to archived backups and records of deletions that are no longer reasonably accessible. We dispose of all Personally Identifiable Information in a manner that prevents loss, theft, misuse, or unauthorized access.

**7\. ACCESS.**

You are permitted to access and, under some circumstances, correct, amend, or delete Personally Identifiable Information maintained by ABBYY. To make such a request, please contact us as provided in Section 19 (Contact Us). We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before fulfilling such requests. You may also delete your name and other Personally Identifiable Information from our databases in accordance with this Section 7 (Access). We will fulfill deletion requests made in accordance with this section within a reasonable time.

**7.1. Discretionary Information.** To allow appropriate control over Personally Identifiable Information, you can contact us, as provided in Section 19 (Contact Us), to access your information to change or update discretionary information that you have previously submitted.

**7.2. Deleting Information.** Finally, if you request, we will remove your name and all other Personally Identifiable Information from our databases. Please understand, however, that it may not be technically or commercially feasible to remove this information completely, due to archived backups and records of deletions that are no longer reasonably accessible. Moreover, we may retain this information in order to maintain accurate records of individuals who have opted-out of receiving marketing communications. In addition, please understand that if you request deletion of your information, you will be unable to utilize associated features of the Website and any associated Products and Services. You may not remove de-identified, anonymous, or aggregate data from our databases.

**8\. DISCLOSURE TO THIRD PARTIES.**

We will not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to unaffiliated third parties without your express consent, or "Opt In", except in the following limited circumstances:

**8.1. ABBYY Site Vendors.** We may employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as hosting or maintaining the Website, providing services related to the Site or the Products and Services, collecting information, responding to and sending electronic mail, or other functions necessary to our business. We may need to share your Personally Identifiable Information with these companies (collectively, " **Site Vendors** ") in order to allow them to perform such functions. We will provide Site Vendors with only that information necessary to perform their functions, and we will not allow them to use your Personally Identifiable Information for any other purpose.

**8.2. Question of Harm.** We may reveal your Personally Identifiable Information to attorneys, private investigator organizations, or law enforcement agencies if we believe (a) that you are at risk of harm from another, or (b) that you are harming or interfering (or will harm or interfere) with others or (c) that you are violating (either intentionally or unintentionally) our Terms of Use or otherwise violating legal rights.

**8.3. Legal.** ABBYY will reveal your Personally Identifiable Information if we are required to do so by law. If we receive legal process calling for the disclosure of your Personally Identifiable Information, we will attempt to notify you via the email address you supplied during registration within a reasonable amount of time before we respond to the request, unless such notification is not permitted.

**8.4. Transfer of Site.** ABBYY may transfer to a third party information it collects, including any Personally Identifiable Information, in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of the business entity responsible for the information under this Notice, provided the acquiring third party has agreed to safeguard your Personally Identifiable Information with protections that in all material respects are the same as or more protective than those set out in this Privacy Notice.

**9\. SECURITY.**

We have put in place security systems designed to prevent unauthorized access to or disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us, and we take all reasonable steps to secure and safeguard this Information. Our Site's password-protected section requires users to give us unique identifiers such as their user name and password. ABBYY employees are required to acknowledge that they understand and will abide by our policies with respect to the confidentiality of Personally Identifiable Information. Additionally, we require ABBYY's Site Vendors to follow security policies and practices that are at least as protective of your information as those contained in our Notice. Moreover, we provide access to our databases containing Personally Identifiable Information on a need-to-know basis only. Our security systems are therefore structured to deter and prevent hackers and others from accessing information you provide to us. We also use software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Please understand, though, that this information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided by or submitted to ABBYY. Due to the nature of Internet communications and evolving technologies, we cannot provide, and therefore expressly disclaim, any assurances that the information you provide us will remain free from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties who, despite our efforts, obtain unauthorized access.

**10\. NOTICE OF SECURITY INCIDENT.**

If we detect, despite the safeguards set out above, an intrusion or other unauthorized access to or use of Personally Identifiable Information (an " **Intrusion** "), we will (i) notify affected users of the Intrusion if, in our discretion, we determine that the information at issue is sensitive, (ii) deliver this notice by the means we deem most efficient under the circumstances (such as, for example, first class mail or email); (iii) use contact information for each affected user that is currently in our files; and (iv) use commercially reasonable efforts to accomplish these steps and effect this notice in a timely manner. To the extent applicable law requires steps in addition to those specified above, we will under all circumstances comply with applicable law.

**11\. QUALITY/DATA INTEGRITY.**

To the extent necessary for those purposes, ABBYY will take reasonable steps to ensure that its systems will not adversely affect the accuracy or integrity of your Personally Identifiable Information. In this regard, however, you should ensure that the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide is accurate and complete.

**12\. MONITORING AND ENFORCEMENT.**

ABBYY uses a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this Privacy Notice and periodically verifies that the Privacy Notice is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible. As part of this self-assessment approach, we engage an independent auditor to test compliance with the Privacy Notice annually. We encourage users to raise any concerns by contacting us, as provided in Section 19 (Contact Us), and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information. If a complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through our internal process, users may report complaints to the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (" **FTC** ").

**13\. ANY INFORMATION LINKED WITH YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION IS PROTECTED AS "PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION."**

To enable us to better understand the characteristics of our Registered Users and to provide services tailored to your needs, we may link (a) the Personally Identifiable Information you have provided with (b) Anonymous Information. If we combine or link any Anonymous Information or other information with your Personally Identifiable Information, the resulting combination will be treated and protected as Personally Identifiable Information under this Privacy Notice. Accordingly, no unrelated third parties will have access to this information, and any of our service providers who are granted access to this information will be bound to protect it in accordance with this Notice.

**14\. BANNER ADS; ADVERTISING PROFILES.**

Our Website may include the use of ad banner partners for the serving and targeting of ads, promotions, and other marketing messages. Ads may be provided, in some cases, by Advertisers. These Advertisers may use traditional banner ads, or other advertising methods, such as advertising using profiles and related Content. An Advertiser may place or utilize its own cookie on your browser, and may use Anonymous Information about your visit to our sites, such as the number of times you have viewed the ad. If the Advertiser requests that you provide to it Personally Identifiable Information, please be aware that this Advertiser's use and collection of this information will be governed by its own Privacy Notice, and not our Privacy Notice. We recommend that you review the Advertiser's Privacy Notice before providing Personally Identifiable Information.

**15\. PARTICIPATION BY CHILDREN AND TEENS; ADVISORY.**

Due to federal law (as reflected in the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act), WE DO NOT ALLOW INDIVIDUALS WHO WE KNOW ARE UNDER 13 TO PARTICIPATE IN OUR SITE OR SERVICES. YOU MUST BE AT LEAST 13 YEARS OLD TO USE OUR SITE AND SERVICES. IF YOU ARE BETWEEN 13 AND THE APPLICABLE AGE OF MAJORITY, PLEASE REVIEW THIS AGREEMENT WITH YOUR PARENT OR GUARDIAN. Please understand that we cannot necessarily tell if a user is providing us with his or her true age.

**16\. NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES.**

From time to time, ABBYY may change its Privacy Notice. If we make any changes regarding disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to third parties, we will attempt to contact you prior to the date the modified Notice is scheduled to take effect. We will post notice of the new Notice at the privacy link on our Website. With respect to Site Visitors, your use of our Site following any such change constitutes your agreement to follow and be bound by the Privacy Notice, as changed. With respect to Registered Users, no such changes will take effect unless and until you have provided us with your consent to such changes.

**17\. OUR AFFILIATES.**

We may choose to share your Personally Identifiable Information with companies closely related to us--our "Affiliates"—for certain purposes under this Privacy Notice, including, without limitation, for the provision of technical support to you and for marketing purposes. By "Affiliate," we mean an entity that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with ABBYY, whether the control results from equity ownership, contract, overlapping management, or otherwise. In this context, "control" means the ability to replace the officers or directors or otherwise materially influence or control management decisions. You agree that our Affiliates will be entitled to enjoy our rights under this Privacy Notice, and in exchange, we agree that we will be responsible for our Affiliates’ conduct under this Privacy Notice, if any Affiliate fails to comply with any obligations hereunder. In any event, we ensure that our Affiliates agree to protect Personally Identifiable Information in a manner no less protective of your interests than the protections set out in this Privacy Notice.

RELATIONSHIP TO TERMS OF USE AND OTHER CONTRACTS.

This Privacy Notice must be read in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions of Use and the provisions of our Terms and Conditions of Use are incorporated herein. To the extent the Terms and Conditions of Use conflict with the terms of this Privacy Notice, the terms of this Privacy Notice will control. Moreover, to the extent this Privacy Notice conflicts with the terms and conditions of any specific agreement you enter with us, the terms and conditions of such specific agreement will control.

**18\. FURTHER RESOURCES.**

If you wish further information concerning privacy policies in general, you should visit <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html>.

**19\. CONTACT US.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Website, please contact us at:

Privacy Officer,  
ABBYY USA Software House, Inc.,  
880 North McCarthy Blvd., Suite 220, Milpitas,CA 95035  
408-457-9777 

**20\. EFFECTIVE DATE.**

The effective date of this Privacy Notice is September 4, 2014.

**COPYRIGHT AND LEGAL NOTICE.** Copyright © 2014 ABBYY. All Rights Reserved.
